Jimmy Alexander Granadino

Los Angeles, California 90043 | (323) 868-1802 | jimmy.granadino@gmail.com | http://jimmygranadino.com

SUMMARY

I'm an enthusiastic solutions-driven developer with an eye towards implementations that optimize business intelligence functions. As an analyst by experience and a creative at heart pushing me forward, I deconstruct challenges to their base components to find efficient outcomes while utilizing my strength of bringing people together for cross-departmental collaboration.

SKILLS

Skills: JavaScript, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, jQuery, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, React.js, Next.js, Vue.js, RESTful APIs, CRUD Operations, Data Analysis, Financial Reporting, Project Management, Financial Modeling **Languages:** English, Spanish (professional proficiency)

EXPERIENCE

USC Credit Union | Los Angeles, CA

Nov. 2019 – May 2020

Real Estate Associate

- Shifted the Real Estate department from a paper loan file process by implementing a paperless software solution where I modeled a fully digital workflow during the COVID-19 crisis.
- Lead training of seasoned Real Estate personnel and re-assigned employees on loan packaging software capabilities and best practices under short notice with an immediate directive of becoming Work From Home capable.
- Aggregated data for reporting purposes related to various KPIs on a weekly, monthly and quarterly basis.

Blacksheep | Sydney, NSW

Dec. 2017 - Jul. 2018

Music Performance Residency

• Entertained patrons with carefully curated selection of music utilizing precise audio mixing and professional music production software while communicating safety needs to hospitality personnel on a weekly basis.

SmartBiz Loans | San Francisco, CA

Sep. 2016 – Jul. 2017

Relationship Manager

- Managed a multimillion dollar portfolio of SBA 7(a) loans while working directly directly with business owners from
 dozens of industries throughout the United States and maintained a judicious relationship with senior lending
 partners to engage in prudent lending.
- Compiled and underwrote challenging SBA 7(a) loan packages in accordance with SBA Standard Operating Procedures and loan underwriting criteria as prescribed by partnered banks.
- Exceeded \$1.1MM monthly volume goal on multiple occasions while receiving company recognition.

Bay Federal Credit Union | Santa Cruz, CA

Jul. 2015 - Sep. 2016

Financial Analyst

- Launched and completed automation projects implemented organization-wide to eliminate hours of daily/weekly duties in various departments using SQL, VBA, and relevant programming languages or tools.
- Analyzed general ledger accounts, generated variance reporting, completed quarterly federal regulatory reports in partnership with Finance Manager, and produced monthly financial statements for board and senior leadership.
- Lead on reconciliation of multiple vendor platforms ensuring integrity of data, analytics and liquidity models.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Aug. 2020

Software Engineering Immersive

University of California, Santa Cruz

Dec. 2014